{"tossups": [{"question": "A \u201cpausing\u201d in this process can lead to the beginning of the surveillance method of no-go decay, andaids in the process of folding. Sites in this process include the exit site, the peptidyl site, and the A site. Thestart of this process is supported by proteins called (*)  initiation factors and includes the production ofmethionine. Elongation is the phase that occurs between the start and stop codons during this process. tRNAs carryattached amino acids and anticodons that complement the mRNA decoded during this process. Proteins aresynthesized in the ribosomes in, for 10 points, what process that follows transcription?", "answer": "eukaryotic translation ", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>eukaryotic translation</u></b>", "acceptable": ["eukaryotic translation"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The mit\u2019a was a public labor requirement in this empire, which made heavy use of the verticalarchipelago agriculture system. Tambos and qullqas were often built along this empire\u2019s roads, while itsmessengers used strings of knots called (*)  quipu. A civil war in this empire was won by a son born outside itsroyal family, and who allegedly ordered the execution of his brother. That leader of this empire was ransomed for aroom full of gold and two rooms full of silver, though Spanish conquistadors killed him anyways. Huascar andAtahualpa led, for 10 points, what South American empire conquered by Francisco Pizzaro?", "answer": "Inca n Empire ", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Inca n Empire</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Inca n Empire"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one song from this film, the singer states \u201cI\u2019ve got this feeling that won\u2019t subside / I look at youand I fantasize\u201d and \u201cnow I\u2019ve got you in my sights / with these\u201d title objects. In a duet used in this film\u2019ssoundtrack, a woman sings \u201coh baby, my sweet baby, you\u2019re the one\u201d after a man asks \u201cSylvia, how do youcall your lover boy?\u201d (*) \u201cHungry Eyes\u201d by Eric Carmen and \u201cLove is Strange\u201d by Mickey &amp; Sylvia are in thesoundtrack to this film, which includes a notable lift performed to the lyrics \u201cI\u2019ve had the time of my life.\u201d For 10points, name this 1987 film starring Jennifer Grey as \u201cBaby\u201d and Patrick Swayze as a dance instructor at a Catskillsresort.", "answer": "Dirty Dancing  ", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Dirty Dancing</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Dirty Dancing"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A \u201cvirtual\u201d form of this quantity is performed along a virtual displacement. A principle partlynamed for this quantity defines it as equal to one-half mass times the difference between two squaredvelocities. The magnetic force has none of this quantity, and in an Atwood machine only gravity causes a (*)non-zero value of this quantity. Mechanical power is defined as this amount divided by the change in time. For 10points, name this quantity measured in Joules and often described as the change in energy, equal to the dot productof force and displacement.", "answer": "mechanical work ", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>mechanical work</u></b>", "acceptable": ["mechanical work"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one story, this character misunderstands the phrase \u201cthere\u2019s an east wind coming.\u201d This charactermarries a governess who is the daughter of a Captain and inherits a large treasure found in the AndamanIslands. This character\u2019s narration is described as \u201cpandering to popular taste,\u201d and an analysis of thischaracter\u2019s watch reveals that his father inherited wealth but was an alcoholic. (*) Mary Morstan marries thischaracter, who worked as an army surgeon before he was wounded in Afghanistan, and narrates many proceedingsthat begin at 221B Baker Street. For 10 points, name this companion of Sherlock Holmes.", "answer": "Dr. John H. Watson ", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Dr. John H. Watson</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Dr. John H. Watson"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The motif for one piece of this type is the eight-note sequence \u201cG-G sharp-F-E-G sharp-A-Fsharp-G,\u201d and may have been based on a Bach piece for four voices ending with a B flat major chord. Thatnotably-complicated piece was originally written for Quartet no. [number] 13 by Ludwig (*) van Beethoven.Compositions of this type usually begin with a subject repeated throughout the exposition, followed by entries indifferent keys. Beethoven wrote a \u201cGrosse\u201d [gross] type of this composition paired in another work with a Toccatain D minor. For 10 points, Bach wrote \u201c The Art of \u201d what type of work?", "answer": "fugue (prompt on string quartet prior to the first mention of \u201cBach\u201d) ", "subcategory": "Music", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>fugue</u></b>", "acceptable": ["fugue"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on string quartet prior to the first mention of \u201cBach\u201d"}, {"question": "The White Lotus Rebellion caused a silver shortage for one government in this conflict, which waspreceded by the Charter Act expanding trade with that country to private merchants. The navalbombardments of the Napier Affair preceded this conflict, which was announced by the (*)  Palmerston Lettersfollowing Lin Zexu\u2019s closure of the Pearl River Channel. A sequel to this conflict was sparked by the seizure of theArrow , and it ended with the first of the Unequal Treaties, which was signed in Nanking and which ceded HongKong. For 10 points, name this conflict over the trade of narcotics in China.", "answer": "Opium Wars (accept First Opium War or Second Opium War) ", "subcategory": "Ancient History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Opium Wars</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Opium Wars"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept First Opium War or Second Opium War"}, {"question": "A book titled for this field introduced the terminology  sub specie aeternitatis  to describe what isuniversally true regardless of reality. In another book titled for this field, the naturalistic fallacy was outlinedby G.E. Moore. The Kantian area of this field focuses on the (*) Categorical Imperative, and other areas of its\u201cnormative\u201d branch include utilitarianism. G.E.M. Anscombe popularized the \u201cvirtue\u201d subfield of, for 10 points,what branch of philosophy that titles a book by Baruch Spinoza and is concerned with the difference between rightand wrong?", "answer": "ethic s (or ethic al philosophy; accept moral s or moral philosophy) ", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>ethic s</u></b>", "acceptable": ["ethic s"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or ethic al philosophy; accept moral s or moral philosophy"}, {"question": "Daphne was the daughter of a god of one of these places, and Arethusa was turned into a spring aftershe was pursued by another god of these places. Scamander, a god of one of these places, tried to kill Achillesduring the Trojan War, while the father of the Sirens, (*)  Achelous, another god associated with these places,lost a wrestling match with Heracles. The Phlegethon is a fiery one of these locations, another of which is associatedwith forgetfulness. For 10 points, name these physical features in Greek myth, which include the Lethe and Styx.", "answer": "river s (prompt on more general answers like bodies of water ) ", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>river s</u></b>", "acceptable": ["river s"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on more general answers like bodies of water"}, {"question": "In one story by this author, a man waves at a three-masted Brazilian ship, leading him to suffer fromfever and nightmares as he is possessed by the title character. In another story by this officer, a prostitutehides in a church tower and rings its bells every day after using a (*)  cheese knife to stab the title Prussianofficer. This author of \u201cThe Horla\u201d also wrote about Mathilde Loisel, who attends a ball hosted by the Ministry ofEducation and loses the title piece of jewelry, which turns out to be fake. For 10 points, name this French author of\u201cMademoiselle Fifi\u201d and \u201cThe Necklace.\u201d", "answer": "Guy de Maupassant ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Guy de <b><u>Maupassant</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Guy de Maupassant"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An emigrant to Germany nicknamed \u201ccurveball\u201d provided false intelligence about this country thatled to the formation of the \u201cCoalition of the Willing.\u201d A large statue in Firdos Square was toppled during aninvasion of this country. The \u201cTorture Memos\u201d authorized the use of (*)  enhanced interrogation techniques inthis country, whose ruler was found hiding near a farmhouse in Tikrit seven months after the U.S.S.   AbrahamLincoln  hosted the \u201cmission accomplished\u201d speech. The CIA tortured detainees at the Abu Ghraib prison in, for 10points, what country led by Saddam Hussein and invaded by the U.S. in 2003?", "answer": "Republic of Iraq ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Republic of <b><u>Iraq</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Republic of Iraq"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a painting from this place, a woman in a pink dress with white frill is in a seated  mudra  positionbehind a woman wearing red and orange pants and with a white flower above her left ear. In anotherpainting from this place, an old woman in black watches over a nude woman lying on a white sheet. Anotherpainting of people from this place includes a blue (*) idol on the left as a boy reaches up for a piece of fruit. Thatwork meant to be read right to left shows three women with a child and an old woman covering her head. For 10points, name this island setting of When Will You Marry?  and Spirit of the Dead Watching , both by Paul Gauguin.", "answer": "Tahiti ", "subcategory": "Painting", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Tahiti</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Tahiti"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In 2019, Ralph Northam and CSX announced an expansion of this organization\u2019s operations inVirginia, while, in 2015, eight people were killed in an accident caused by a distracted employee of thisorganization in Philadelphia. Like the postal service, this organization has struggled with lack of (*)profitability in rural areas, but has the added issue of not owning most of its infrastructure. RichardAnderson and William Flynn are recent CEOs of this organization, and have ended full dining service andtried to cut long-distance routes to focus on the northeast corridor. For 10 points, name this Americanpassenger rail service.", "answer": "Amtrak ", "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Amtrak</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Amtrak"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poet described watching a train \u201click the Valleys up / And stop to feed itself at Tanks.\u201d Inanother poem, this author describes \u201cthe winds\u201d as \u201cfutile...to a Heart in port\u201d and exclaims \u201cMight I butmoor - tonight - / In thee!\u201d Another of this author\u2019s poems describes passing \u201cfields of gazing grain\u201d and how\u201cthe Dews drew quivering and Chill\u201d when a figure (*) \u201cpassed us.\u201d In that poem by this author of \u201cI like to seeit lap the Miles,\u201d the narrator rides in a carriage that \u201cheld but just ourselves / and immortality.\u201d For 10 points, namethis author of \u201cWild nights\u201d and \u201cBecause I could not stop for Death.\u201d", "answer": "Emily Dickinson ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Emily <b><u>Dickinson</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Emily Dickinson"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Polignac\u2019s conjecture and Legendre\u2019s conjecture concern gaps between these numbers. For a largeN, the probability of randomly generating one of these numbers is about 1 divided by log(N). TheMiller-Rabin test and the AKS test are methods of checking if a number belongs to this group, whose (*)Sophie Germain subset are used to determine \u201csafe\u201d examples of these numbers for public key cryptography. TheSieve of Eratosthenes can also be used to find these numbers, whose Mersenne subgroup is the group of thesenumbers that are 1 less than a power of 2, like 3, 7, and 31. For 10 points, name these numbers that can only befactored by themselves and 1.", "answer": "prime numbers (or prime s; accept Mersenne prime or Sophie Germain prime )", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>prime numbers</u></b>", "acceptable": ["prime numbers"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or prime s; accept Mersenne prime or Sophie Germain prime"}, {"question": "Under acidic conditions, the opening of an epoxide results in one of these functional groups gettingplaced at the less-substituted position. In a two-step process, an alkene is first reacted with mercury (II)acetate and then sodium borohydride to form into the (*) anti-Markovnikov one of these functional groups.Reacting PCC with the primary form of one of these functional groups results in the formation of an aldehyde, andthese functional groups readily form hydrogen bonds with water due to their oxygen-hydrogen bond. For 10 points,name this functional group whose simplest molecules are methanol and ethanol.", "answer": "alcohol group ", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>alcohol group</u></b>", "acceptable": ["alcohol group"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Stones are thrown at three pillars in a re-enactment of the Stoning of the Devil as part of this activity.The Miqat needs to be crossed for Ihram to be attained at the beginning of this activity, during which menare required to wear two white cloths. The Umrah is a form of this activity undertaken at any (*) point duringthe year, rather than during its traditional dates. While performing this activity, individuals walk between two hillsnamed Safa and Marwah seven times, and visit the Zamzam Well, which is in the same city as the Great Mosque.For 10 points, name this annual Islamic pilgrimage to Mecca.", "answer": "Hajj (accept Umrah before mention) ", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Hajj</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Hajj"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Umrah before mention"}, {"question": "In one film set in this city, the reporter Mike Connor offers to marry Tracy Lord after she cancelsher wedding with George Kittredge, but she remarries her ex-husband instead. That film, starring JamesStewart, Cary Grant, and Katherine Hepburn, is partially titled for this city, which also titles a film followingAndrew Beckett, a lawyer suffering from (*) AIDS. Bill Conti composed \u201cGonna Fly Now\u201d for a film set in thiscity; that song is played as the title character does push ups and runs through this city, culminating in a climb up thesteps of its Museum of Art. For 10 points, name this city, the setting of Sylvester Stallone\u2019s Rocky .", "answer": "Philadelphia (accept The Philadelphia Story as that is the first film mentioned; the second film", "subcategory": "Other Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Philadelphia</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Philadelphia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Della Torre family lost control of this city after the 1277 Battle of Desio. One ruler of this citydefected after its government recalled him from the Siege of Brescia, and besieged this city to end itsAmbrosian Republic. This city was captured by Francis (*)  I after the Battle of Marignano, and became territoryof the Holy Roman Empire after the death of Francesco II. Condottieri who led this city include Ottone Visconti andLudovico Sforza. For 10 points, name this city-state and Duchy that formed the Italian League with the Papal States,Naples, Venice, and Florence.", "answer": "Duchy of Milan ", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Duchy of Milan</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Duchy of Milan"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this novel, a naval commander is banished after attempting to seduce a woman at a party, andlater falls down a well. Another character in this novel was made Keeper of Horses before leaving andnaming themselves a \u201cgreat sage.\u201d That character is sealed under a (*)  mountain for five hundred years beforeassisting with an effort to retrieve Buddhist scrolls from Vulture Peak. In this novel, a part-human, part-pig characteraccompanies a monk and a monkey who wields the staff Ruyi Jingu Bang and has mastered 72 transformations. ZhuBajie, Xuanzng, and Sun Wukong travel to India in, for 10 points, what classical Chinese novel?", "answer": "Journey to the West  (or Xi You Ji ; accept Monkey ) ", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Journey to the West</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Journey to the West"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Xi You Ji ; accept Monkey"}]}